<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jay Blogs</title>
    <description>Where I write my experiences as Software Developer, with bits of rants growing up as a gay guy and some societal issues.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:36:45 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:36:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reply to &quot;Should Old Friends and Days of Long Ago Should Be Forgotten?&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, young Jay, your grammar sucks and it’s ironic considering that you answered this question during the time that you were taking your Journalism class in Bangkal High School under Prof. Neri&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway for it’s a no for me. These old friends, together with our old memories with them, they are the reason why and where we are right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So! Story time, I’ve had an old friend whom helped me pass during my Grade School days. But eventually, there was time that we’ve had to be separated because my family had to move to another city. We haven’t forgotten each other, in fact we often see each other’s posts in Facebook because we’re friends, but, we do not really interact with each other, we just know what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the “exciting” part. Campaign period for Philippines 2022 National Elections have officially started, surprise surprise, most of them are Kakampink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I know you ask?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well Facebook, for some reason, decided that I should see my old friends post again because they are kakampinks. If my memory serves me right, I started to see their post when Pasiglaban (Election Campaign of VP Leni Robredo in Emerald Ave., Pasig City to be President) campaign took place. And since then, I’ve been interacting with them through comments on their shared post. I could’ve shared posts too but oh well, I have soooo many BBM supporter relatives so I just didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 20:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/reply-to-should-old-friends-and-days-of-long-ago-should-be-forgotten/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/reply-to-should-old-friends-and-days-of-long-ago-should-be-forgotten/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>school</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up my first blog website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/my-first-blog-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/my-first-blog-post/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&apos;m Gay. Nerd.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m Gay. Nerd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently watched Netflix’s Heartstopper and I just related so much to Charlie. There’s never been an instance that a character in a movie or series, that made me feel so seen as a person.
Charlie is someone is who is very introverted, and good at math (while I am skilled at programming and I also like computers), minus the part that he is good at music because for the life of me I can’t even read music notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming out today was probably late since I’ve already known myself as gay years years ago, but I’m just the type of gay guy who is very discreet, and I just thought that nothing is gonna change even if I come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I just really wanna get this out of my chest. There is still part of me that wants to be seen as the real me. I tried to keep it to my immediate family and select relatives only and a very few close friends but I feel like in this time I shouldn’t be scared anything anymore. This is me and if somebody can’t accept me so be it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here ya go ya’ll, I’m part of the rainbow 🙂 🏳️‍🌈 ❤️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/img/2022-04-27-im-gay-nerd/279397337_1585283891856984_6085453319711835818_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:46:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/im-gay-nerd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/im-gay-nerd/</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>lgbt+</category>
        
        <category>heartstopper</category>
        
        <category>charlie</category>
        
        
        <category>lgbt+</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Coming Out Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been 3-4 years since I discovered I was gay, it was a really hard time for me, but I think I’m ready to tell my story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still remember before starting Grade 10, I prayed to God, hoping that no one would bully me anymore and that I’ll have more friends this time around. (I was bullied for a lot of reasons back in Grade 6 to 9, and added the factor that I didn’t had a lot of friends because I was super shy and don’t know how to talk. It was terrible basically)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wish came true and I was super grateful, then with this new friend group I met a guy. He’s a really funny one, he would always make us laugh but specially me, his jokes, because of that I think out of all people we’ve been the most closest. I would describe him as my best friend at the time to be honest.
Then one day he told me he’s got crush on a girl, someone that is out of our circle but pretty close to us. He was rejected and I don’t blame the girl because she’s pretty much the aral muna type of person. This is when my best friend started to be sad, really really sad, not just because of the rejection but also some family issues that affected him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed beside him, but most specially when he told me that he could possibly have a mental disorder that greatly affected his mood. I remember searching up articles on how to help someone with this. I was there when he needed someone to talk to, be it in chat, the class or even outside the class. Still remember that special moment when we sat on the side of a bridge, him telling his problems about his mom and just really really sad stuff. I was there through most of it, specially when he tried hurting himself, talking about suicide because he can’t bear it anymore. I begged him not to do it during the several times that he wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day one girl came to our lives, she’s not in our inner circle as well but she’s close to some of us. Soon, she and my best friend started to hangout more often. His mood definitely improved since they started to hangout and I don’t know why. I also felt at the time that I was being jealous at how they’re close. That feeling that you’re not needed anymore and that you should probably just let them be because that is the best for them, most specially for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I couldn’t keep those feelings and I think I admitted that I like him, or I was gay. It didn’t ended so well and we weren’t that close anymore after that. I don’t blame him, it must have been stressful for him already because of his problems, and me admitting must have caused him more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the most traumatic part of it is that I blamed myself why our friend group broke, even till this day. It was never been the same since. That I ended up loosing the friends I longed for, just because of my realization of my feelings for a guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I didn’t blamed myself for is that I was there for someone when they really needed it. At that time my painful memories of being bullied was still there and feeling alone. And I don’t want that to happen to anyone else, most specially to the person that I like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that is my definition of love at the time, let go the person you love the most if it means that they would be better, without you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/my-coming-out-story/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/my-coming-out-story/</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>lgbt+</category>
        
        
        <category>lgbt+</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing The Coffee Lounge™</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I introduce The Coffee Lounge™&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A five-star coffee shop, located in the heart of Metro Manila.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serving exceptional coffee, partnered with our famous bread products, your experience in The Coffee Lounge will be nothing short of extravagant and relaxing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t exist in real world as of now, yet it represents a milestone in my grand scheme plan of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 Years from now, The Coffee Lounge™ is going to be one of the last businesses that I’ll establish before going abroad to finally be free from the society that I am currently in, and live my life the way I wanted it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the hardships that I’m going through right now, countless of sleepless nights, struggles in school, lots of existential crisis, it’ll all be worth it in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much sa naging graphic designer ng website at UI / UX Engineer ng The Coffee Lounge™ website Tin-Tin Rodriguez. Your works are just amazing, hire niyo na po siya please XD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit our website at:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://the-coffee-lounge.pages.dev/&quot;&gt;https://the-coffee-lounge.pages.dev/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-coffee-lounge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/the-coffee-lounge/</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Camp Buddy Toolbox using PySimpleGUI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I once wanted to create a Discord chatbot that speaks exactly like Keitaro, however, none have written a dialog extractor specifically for Camp Buddy, so I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lonewanderer27/Camp-Buddy-Dialog-Extractor&quot;&gt;Camp Buddy Dialog Extractor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that program is a command line application, meaning a user would have to know how to use a terminal which is not very user friendly… What if someone who’s inexperienced in coding just wants to have fun with their friends, talking to Keitaro or Hiro in their Discord server, like I once wanted…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought to myself.. why not make an app that can extract scripts from Camp Buddy? (and more that I can think of in the future)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2022-06-09-making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/Screenshot_Extract_Dialogs_Tab.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sooooooo above me is a screenshot of the tool that I’m currently making for a Visual Novel game. It mainly targets those who want to make a python chat bot that speaks exactly like the characters from the Visual Novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extracting-assets-tab&quot;&gt;Extracting Assets Tab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2022-06-09-making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/172808192-31553218-949d-432a-a740-68266242f98a.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GUI doesn’t become unresponsive thanks to perform_long_operation. And the write_event_value made it easy to pass the current file that is being extracted, as well as the current progress of the extraction from a separate python program&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2022-06-09-making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/172815391-6f95e611-3f80-4875-a586-baf5aae3d6a3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I kinda wish this also works in the QT port as I prefer the look of that instead of Tkinter. But this will do for now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extracting-scripts-tab&quot;&gt;Extracting Scripts Tab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The layout tools worked very well in keeping the check boxes organized&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2022-06-09-making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/172815459-afddc0de-7ac3-4be4-9d96-76cfe86529dc.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-window&quot;&gt;About Window&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the About window of GNOME / GTK apps so I made mine look similar to it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2022-06-09-making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/172815544-67924be4-00f8-4016-a34e-a96c6b82a200.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Github Repo link is here for anyone who wants to look at the code, warning it’s spaghetti code:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lonewanderer27/Camp-Buddy-Toolbox&quot;&gt;https://github.com/lonewanderer27/Camp-Buddy-Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I am legally required to disclose the code anyway since I used and modified (a bit) the code of the extractor program (which is GPL-3 licensed)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 17:12:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/making-camp-buddy-toolbox-using-pysimplegui/</guid>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am a Tech-Nerd</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a tech-nerd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collecting a bunch of electronics, opening their insides to see how they work and experimenting with them has been my hobby since I was 11 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s so much more, I dream the likes of Elon Musk, Bill Gates who own multi-national companies that continues to push the capabilities of our technology, innovating in every where possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also strive to change how the society perceives Programming and Tech related Jobs, you are not just sitting in a chair all day waiting for something to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can create something meaningful that could change the humanity forever, right from your very own keyboard and monitor.”  ~ Jay2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#PERDEVCAREERS
#STEMCOMPROG
#FUTUREIT&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/i-am-a-tech-nerd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/i-am-a-tech-nerd/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;ml-1 mr-1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;target=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;_blank&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fab fa-twitter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-css highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#999988&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;font-style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;italic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#a61717&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#e3d2d2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;js&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// alertbar later&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scroll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scrollTop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;280&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeOut&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;python&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;redcarpet&apos;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Redcarpet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;c&quot;&gt;C&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/first-mass-produced/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/first-mass-produced/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/education/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/education/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
